Guide to the Pulitzer Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Pulitzer Papers
1883-1936,
1885-1912 (bulk)
Pulitzer, Joseph, 1847-1911.
63 boxes
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#1033
4079242
Biographical Note
Jopseph Pulitzer was a newspaper publisher of the St. Louis Dispatch and The New York World.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and business documents of Joseph Pulitzer, the Pulitzer family, and the operation of the ST. LOUIS POST-DISPATCH. Also, drafts of Thomas E. Eichhorst's dissertation, Representative and Reporter: Joseph Pulitzer as a Missouri State Representative.
Arrangement
Chronological.
Subjects
Eichhorst, Thomas E.; Families--Missouri--Saint Louis.; Newspaper publishing--Missouri--Saint Louis.; Politicians.; Journalists.; St. Louis post-dispatch.
Acquisition
M-59 Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr. Gift
Related Material
The material directly relating to Pulitzer's New York newspaper, THE WORLD, forms a separate collection. See THE WORLD (New York) - Papers.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - A-C (Box 1)
  - D-Ma (Box 2)
  - Me-Z (Box 3)
- Series II: Chronological Files, 1883-1936
  - Undated Items (Box 4)
  - 1883-1885 (Box 5)
  - 1886 (Box 6)
  - 1887-1888 (Box 7)
  - 1889-1898 (Box 8)
  - 1899 (Box 9)
  - 1900 January -March (Box 10)
  - 1900 April -August (Box 11)
  - 1900 September -December (Box 12)
  - 1900--Bills and Receipts (Box 13-14)
  - 1901 January -May (Box 15)
  - 1901 June -December (Box 16)
  - 1901 Bills and Receipts (Box 17)
  - 1902 Bills and Receipts (Box 18)
  - 1902 January -June 15 (Box 19)
  - 1902 June 16-September (Box 20)
  - 1902 October -December (Box 21)
  - 1903 Bills and Receipts (Box 22)
  - 1903 January -March (Box 23)
  - 1903April -June (Box 24)
  - 1903 July -September 12 (Box 25)
  - 1903 September 13-December (Box 26)
  - 1904--Bills and Receipts (Box 27)
  - 1904 January -February (Box 28)
  - 1904 March-May (Box 29)
  - 1904 June -August (Box 30)
  - 1904 September -December (Box 31)
  - 1905 January -February (Box 32)
  - 1905 March-April (Box 33)
  - 1905 May -August (Box 34)
  - 1905 September -December (Box 35)
  - 1905--Bills and Receipts (Box 36)
  - 1906--Bills and Receipts (Box 37)
  - 1906 January -April (Box 38)
  - 1906 May -July (Box 39)
  - 1906 August -December (Box 40)
  - 1907 January -February15 (Box 41)
  - 1907 February16-April (Box 42)
  - 1907 May -September (Box 43)
  - 1907 October -December (Box 44)
  - Bills and Receipts (Box 44)
  - 1908--Bills and receipts (Box 45-46)
  - 1908 January -April (Box 47)
  - 1908 May -December (Box 48)
  - 1908-1911--Account Books of the yacht Liberty (Box 49)
  - 1909 (Box 50)
  - 1909 Bills and Receipts (Box 51)
  - 1910 Bills and Receipts (Box 52)
  - 1910 (Box 53)
  - 1911 Bills and Receipts (Box 54)
  - 1911 January -August 19 (Box 55)
  - 1911 August 20-December (Box 56)
  - Account Book (Box 56)
  - 1912-1916 (Box 57)
  - 1917 (Box 58)
  - 1978-1936 (Box 59)
  - Printed Materials (Box 60)
  - Thomas E. Eichhorst dissertation "Representative and Reporter: Joseph Pulitzer as a Missouri State Representative--rough drafts (Box 61)
  - Thomas E. Eichhorst dissertation "Representative and Reporter: Joseph Pulitzer as a Missouri State Representative--final draft (Box 62)
  - Undated material (Box 63)
  - Joseph Pulitzer's watch fob (Box 63)
    (with his initials on one face, the logo of The World on the reverse and a miniature of his mother inside)